Il y a mille-quatre-cent ans
un simple marchand
qui ne savait ni lire ni écrire
a amené un profond changement en Arabie.
Son nom était Muhammad.
Aujourd'hui, son influence
s'étend dans le monde entier
les États-Unis inclus...
Voici son histoire.
Et l'histoire de millions d'Américains qui suivent
ses enseignements de prophète ultime de Dieu.
La majorité du financement de Muhammad
Legacy of a Prophet vient de
CORPORATION FOR PUBLIC BROADCASTING
et de THE DAVID AND
LUCILE PACKARD FOUNDATION
ARABIAN BULK TRADE
SABADIA FAMILY FOUNDATION,
THE EL-HIBRI FOUNDATION
la FONDATION IRFAN KATHWARI
et MIR IMRAN.
Des fonds supplémentaires ont aussi
été apportés par de nombreux individus et entités.
Il n'était ni grand et fin
ni petit et gros.
Quand il regardait quelqu'un
il le regardait dans les yeux.
C'était le plus généreux des Hommes
le plus vrai dans ses paroles
le plus patient de tous
et ses ascendants étaient des plus nobles.
Toute personne qui l'aurait croisé dirait
jamais avant ou après l'avoir vu
n'ais-je vu pareille personne
Muhammad, décrit par un de ses contemporains.
Muhammad est un Homme qui a été confronté
à une situation qui semblait inextricable.
Il vivait dans un continent où
les gens s'entretuaient littéralement
dans une vendetta infinie, entraînant
un déferlement de guerres et de violence.
Sentant que la société allait
s'effondrer et qu'il n'y avait pas d'espoir.
Il leur a donné de l'espoir à lui seul
En l'espace de 23 ans
il a amené la paix et redonné de l'espoir
à l'Arabie et un nouveau modèle pour le monde.
L'islam, la religion de Muhammad,
formée d'abord en Arabie
compte aujourd'hui 1.2 milliard
d'adeptes de par le monde.
Aux États-Unis il y a
environ 7 millions de musulmans
et c'est ici la religion avec
la croissance la plus rapide
et la plus diverse.
Comme c'est le cas pour l'Amérique elle même,
les musulmans ici viennent des quatre coins du monde.
Ils ont un lien en commun
pas seulement dans leur foi
et dans leurs mosquées
mais dans cette histoire de Muhammad,
qui leur sert d'exemple.
Elle leur apprend comment se comporter
comment être un citoyen constructif
comment être un bon parent,
et comment être un bon enfant
comment chercher le savoir et la vérité.
Ce sont des valeurs qui se retrouvent
le plus, pour les musulmans,
dans la vie de Muhammad.
Dans le Coran, Allah dit que Muhammad est
le meilleur exemple à suivre.
Et qu'il est le modèle pour gérer
nos relations interpersonelles
et quand on est dans une
position d'authorité
comment essayer d'implémenter
la justice et la loi
Le prophète Muammad, il demandait
à ses contemporains
aimez vous votre créateur?
Aimez vos semblables d'abord en les servant.
Qu'est-ce que ça veut dire?
Ça veut dire que tout ce blabla,
I love God et companie.
Si tu veux vraiment [remplir ta mission], tu sais
oublie le blabla, agis et sors.
Tu veux servir Dieu, sers les gens.
Quelle meilleure manière de servir les gens
que de risquer notre vie pour les sauver.
Le 11 septembre a changé
la face du monde
et il a aussi mis les musulmans
dans le viseur
les musulmans font face à beaucoup
d'hostilité
Mais c'est aussi une époque
de changement.
Beaucoup de gens veulent
comprendre ce qu'est l'islam
et comprendre qui était le prophète
et ce que contient le Coran
Qui sont les musulmans et
quelles sont leurs coutumes
Par l'histoire
du prophète Muhammad
nous avons pu faire des rapprochements
et soudainement on peut s'identifier
à des événements d'il y a 1500 ans
et voir que leurs problèmes
ne sont pas obsolètes
ils sont universels.
C'est ce qu'il m'a appris.
Voici l'histoire que les musulmans
ont préservé et transmis
de génération en génération
depuis 1400 ans.
L'histoire d'un marchand,
d'un mari, d'un père,
d'un homme d'état et d'un guerrier
qu'ils considèrent comme le dernier prophète.
L'Homme dont les enseignements
continuent d'influencer leurs vies aujourd'hui.
Muhammad: l'héritage d'un prophète
La vie de Muhammad
est, dans ses détails probablement
plus connue que celle de n'importe quelle autre
figure religieuse antérieure aux temps modernes.
Ses compagnons ont fait attention
à collecter toutes les mémoires
des paroles qu'il a prononcé
et des actes qu'il a effectués.
Une partie de ces traditions
ont pu être ajoutées à posteriori
mais l'essence de l'enseignement me semble très
vraisemblable et il est difficile de réfuter
le fait qu'elles décrivent la
vie d'un homme bien réel.
Selon les sources Islamiques
Muhammad bin Abdullah, ou fils d'Abdullah
est né en l'an 570
dans la ville de la Mecque
en Arabie Saoudite actuelle.
Un poète de l'époque
a dit de La Mecque
qu'elle était aussi insupportable en été qu'en hiver.
Le monde qui vu l'avènement
de Muhammad était cruel
Il y régnaient la faim, la
violence et les guerres tribales.
On n'était rien sans sa tribu
Dans ce monde perilleux, un individu
seul n'avait aucune chance de survie.
Par conséquent, la tribu était la chose
la plus importante et sacrée en Arabie.
C'est une société basée
entièrement sur la méfiance
Et si quelqu'un attaque mon clan
il devient de mon bon droit d'attaquer
quiconque fait partie de son clan.
La justice était confondue
avec la vengeance.
Les Arabes du sixième siècle n'avaient aucunes lois,
aucune religion et aucun
gouvernement en commun.
Dans ce monde perilleux,
Muhammad eut la chance de naître dans la
tribu influente des Quraych de La Mecque.
Mais, son père mourut avant sa naissance, et
sa mère mourut alors qu'il n'avait que 6 ans.
Son oncle, Abu Talib, fut
chargé d'élever le jeune orphelin.
Il est évident qu'il a du beaucoup se
tourmenter de son avenir, que deviendrait-il?
Et par conséquent il devait
être un enfant très introverti.
Muhammad avait cette habitude
de partir dans le désert pour
contempler les étoiles et réfléchir
à la raison de son orphelinage
Et qu'est-ce que lui
réservait l'avenir ?
Les orphelins étaient marginalisés
par conséquent tout le
reste de sa vie, il s'est identifié
aux pauvres et déshérités.
La Mecque du temps de la jeunesse de Muhammad
était un centre religieux et commercial.
située au croisement de deux voies majeures
Les pèlerins venaient de toute
l'Arabie pour vouer un culte
aux centaines d'idoles
qui entouraient la Kaaba
un sanctuaire ancien
situé au coeur de la Ville
Les alentours de la Kaaba étaient
sacrés et il était interdit de s'y battre
La manne financière
des pèlerinages a permis
à un jeune Homme comme Muhammad de
gagner sa vie dans les marchés de la Mecque
Bientôt Muhammad devenait un
commis pour des marchands argentés
enmenant leurs biens sur
des caravanes à travers l'Arabie
Ces voyages lui permirent de rencontrer
de nombreuses autres tribus et communautés
et de s'exposer à
des idées nouvelles.
Il a probablement appris ainsi
les différences entre les tribus.
Rencontré des gens parlant d'autres
langues, croisé des Chrétiens et des Juifs.
Et appris de leur bouche
quelle étaient leurs croyances,
leur religion, leur culture.
Avec ces rencontres, Muhammad
aurait réalisé que pour les Juifs
et les Chrétiens, les saintes
écritures sont cruciales.
Les deux avaient des
textes envoyés par Dieu,
un message sacré délivré aux prophètes
et c'était ainsi que les gens
pouvaient se connecter au Divin.
Alors que Muhammad avait 25 ans,
il y eut un changement énorme dans sa vie.
Une veuve argentée
plus vieille que lui, appelée Khadija
lui demandait de conduire
ses caravanes en Syrie.
Muhammad enmena tout ses biens
et partit avec la caravanne en Syrie,
il fit un travail incroyable.
Et son respect pour lui se
transforma en une admiration.
Et elle se renseigna sur lui
par le biais d'une de ses amies.
Peu après Khadija demanda
à Muhammad de l'épouser
Je t'apprécies du fait
de notre relation, elle dit
et du fait de ta
réputation parmis les tiens
ta fiabilité, ta bonté et ton honnêteté
Et ceci est intéressant,
elle est très belle,
mais elle atteint les 40 ans
elle arrive à sa maturité et son échéance
alors qu'il est un jeune homme de 25 ans
il est orphelin
Et il accepte cette proposition,
qui est arrangée dans la famille
ce qui aboutit en effet à un mariage
Et souvent les gens
ont dit, pour le dénigrer,
que ce mariage avait eu lieu que
parcequ'il l'arrangeait matériellement.
Il avait juste épousé la vieille
veuve pour profiter de son argent
Mais selon moi, il n'y a aucun doute
qu'il avait vraiment aimé Khadidja
Le mariage de Khadidja et
Muhammad découlera en 4 filles
et deux fils morts
dans leur enfance.
C'était un père de famille et un
marchand prospère et respecté
Mais alors qu'il approchait
ses 40 ans, Muhammad
etait de plus en
plus troublé par
les problèmes de
la société Meccane.
En quelques générations,
ils étaient passés de cette existance
brutale dans les steppes d'Arabie
à devenir des banquiers, financiers,
hommes d'affaire, marchands,
avec beaucoup d'argent.
Evidemment, c'était merveilleux, tout
le monde était ravi de cette prosperité
Mais cette époque avait aussi ses travers,
car l'économie de marché, causait
comme nous le voyons trop à
l'Ouest, une grande compétitivité
Les gens n'avaient plus cet impératif de
s'occuper des pauvres et des gens dans le besoin
et des membres affaiblis
de la tribu Quraych
Ils pensaient devoir se concentrer
sur la maximisation de leurs revenus
Leur société était superbe
Leur ville était en pleine croissance
les affaires étaient bonnes
Ils vivaient dans une société prospère
Et lorsque les temps sont prospères
il est facile de devenir hédoniste
De se pencher sur la question de
que sont les plaisirs de la vie (peterson)
Muhammad prenait souvent refuge dans les
montagnes alentours à la Mecque pour y méditer
C'est lors d'un tel voyage, en l'an 610,
que Muhammad vécut une expérience
qui allait changer l'histoire.
Le prophète partait, de temps en temps,
vers un pic appelé Jabal al-Nur,
la montagne de lumière.
Quand on escalade cette montagne,
beaucoup le font encore aujourd'hui
il y a une grotte au sommet
appelée al-Hira en Arabe
dans cette grotte il s'isolait
souvent pour réfléchir
et pour prier
Pour se retrouver seul avec Dieu.
La révélation fut un événement instantané
La descente du ciel fut fracassante
Muhammad fut réveillé d'un assoupissement
et se senti entièrement enveloppé
par une présence Divine terrifiante.
Il a rapporté qu'un
ange semblait l'écraser
dans une étreinte terrifiante
il lui semblait que tout son souffle
de vie s'échappait de son corps
Et une voix lui a dit "Récite!"
Muhammad dit: "non, je
ne suis pas un perroquet. "
La voix reitéra
Recite
Et l'étreinte se renforca pendant
que lui, à la limite de ses capacités
Muhammad ressentit en lui
les premiers mots
d'un nouvel évangile, en
Arabe, qui sortaient de ses levres.
Celà veut dire "Récite au
nom de ton Dieu qui t'a créé"
L'Islam était né
Et le prophète, ayant
reçu la parole divine,
commença à trembler dans une peur suprême
parceque la réalité divine est
sans pareille à l'expérience humaine
Lorsqu'il sortit de la grotte
Lorsqu'il parvint à s'échapper
de la grotte, il se retourna
et vu l'Archange s'étendre
sur le ciel tout entier
Peu importe où il
regardait, Gabriel était là.
Ce n'est pas une simple image angélique,
c'est une présence, une entité, un pouvoir.
Voilà comment l'inexprimable
incompréhensible, intrinsèquement
transcendant et indescriptible Dieu
se présente à nous.
Voilà un événement qui
changea tout dans sa vie
Et en redescendant de la
montagne, il tremble encore.
Pour moi c'est un état de choc
Voici quelqu'un qui est parti
à la recherche de la transcendance
et la transcendance lui a
répondu.
Muhammad a été si perturbé par cette expérience
qu'il a commencé par penser être possédé
Il est rentré chez lui
directement pour voir Khadija.
Il s'est jeté à son cou et lui
a demandé, "protège moi"
"couvre moi, tiens moi compagnie
jusqu'à ce que l'horreur soit passée"
Khadija a été là
pour le rassurer
"Il a demandé, "suis-je devenu un kahin,
un voyant fou?"
Elle a répondu
Non mon cheri, ce n'est pas
dans les manières de Dieu
Tu as vu une révélation divine.
Le message reçu par Muhammad
sur la montagne de lumière était simple:
Il avait pour mission de diffuser les
paroles du seul et unique vrai Dieu
Mais Muhammad doutait encore
de la véracité de son expérience.
Khadija pensa qu'il serait bon de consulter
son cousin Waraqa
qui était Chrétien.
Elle lui dit, nous devons aller voir
quelqu'un qui est compétent sur ces sujets
Parceque, si on te dit que tu
vas reçevoir un message Divin
eh bien il y a eu des
messages antérieurs
Donc allons voir Waraqa qui
connaît les saintes écritures
Il connaît la Torah
et les Evangiles.
Dès que Waraqa fut mis
au courant, il s'exclama
Muhammad est le Prophète
qui amènera la révélation
du Dieu unique aux Arabes
et il prévint Muhammad
que sa mission
ne serait pas aisée
Il lui dit, ta tribu va te rejeter,
et ils te chasseront de ta ville
Ces révélations ne sont jamais parvenues à
un Homme qui n'a ensuite pas été persécuté
Car celà revient simplement à un
changement de paradigme brutal
Au bout d'un moment, Muhammad comprit
que les messages qu'il recevait coincidaient
bien avec des idées qu'il connaissait
des traiditions Juives et Chrétiennes.
Par exemple le fait de
l'existence des prophètes
Qu'il y a des gens capables de
recevoir des messages du Divin
et il commença à comprendre
qu'il en faisait partie
Quand nous pensons aux
prophécies en amérique
nous pensons au Moïse
joué par Charlton Heston
la barbe dans le vent, le baton de berger
Et le prophète porte des vêtements en
haillons, en s'exclamant devant la foule
Il s'exclame comme un possédé.
Dans le monde Islamique
le prophète n'a rien de celà
Ici c'est une personne prise
contre son gré parmi les siens
Il est choisi par
Dieu et ne peut pas
s'échapper de la machine
divine, d'une certaine manière
Il faut penser comme une
société bédouine tribale pense
Quelle est la pire chose
qui puisse vous arriver ?
Ce n'est pas de mourir,
c'est d'avoir la honte sur vous
Ainsi, je suis
assez sûr de l'idée
que pour lui la peur de la
honte était quelque chose de clé
Imaginez la double honte
il va perdre la face et
être humilié devant sa tribu
et il va être humilié devant
Allah qui lui a confié ce message
Une des particularités qui m'a
attiré en tant que non musulman
qui vient d'un environnement assez hétéroclite
était son humilité. Son humanité.
Kevin James est un pompier
superviseur de Brooklyn, New York
qui s'est converti à
l'Islam dans sa jeunesse.
J'ai senti une connexion personelle à lui
Et je pense qu'il y a environ un milliard
de musulmans qui pourraient en dire de même
cette affinité personnelle
qu'ils ressentent avec lui.
Le fait qu'il ait grandi orphelin.
Je ne suis pas orphelin mais
de part ma position dans la société
je me suis toujours senti ostracisé.
Les états unis sont un pays racial
tu es soit noir, blanc,
juif, italien, ceci ou celà
Donc, venant d'une famille mixte, je me
suis senti comme prisonnier des limbes
My père est Natif Americain
et noir et ma mère est Juive.
Ils étaient très a-religieux, limite
athés ou au moins agnostiques
Je me souviens que dans ma
jeunesse on avait une dreidel
pour Hanukkah, on avait un
chandelier dans la maison et aussi
un sapin de noel,
on avait des cadeaux.
Donc, je n'ai jamais pu trop
m'identifier à une religion en particulier
ce qui était encouragé c'était
la discussion, le dialogue, et
la recherche de la vérité.
Donc je suis passé par une periode de recherche
par l'essai et l'erreur, j'ai tâtonné.
Et j'ai fini par tomber, je pense
qu'on peut dire tomber, sur l'Islam
Ce qui m'a intéressé était
l'universalité du message.
Toute religion qui donne un code
de conduite, d'éthique, de vertu et
encourage le respect, la gratitude et
l'obeissance à un Dieu est juste pour l'Islam.
Donc, voici un livre, le noble
Coran, qui valide les autres religions
la diversité de l'humanité
et met la responsabilité de sauver
son âme, sur le dos du croyant.
Le Coran nous apprend que sauver une vie
équivaut à sauver l'humanité.
Voici une des raisons pour
lesquelles je suis devenu pompier
Quelle meilleure vocation que de
sauver les gens,
sauver leurs biens
Il y a eu un autre feu au fond
Okay, voyons ça
Après avoir été pompier je suis devenu
enquèteur sur les incendies criminels
C'est une autre forme de
prévention pour sauver des vies
Bon bah je pense
que la cause est claire
Le pompier va risquer sa vie pour
te sauver, peu importe ta couleur
noir, rouge, musulman, chrétien, athé
Il ne te demandes pas ce que tu
penses et ne regarde pas ta couleur
Il veut juste t'aider à
t'échapper du bâtiment
C'est pourquoi beaucoup disent que être
pompier c'est une vocation, à cause de ce
du don de soi
La volonté de faire passer
les autres avant soi même
Pour être un bon musulman,
il faut servir les autres
En particulier, le prophète a dit,
il a demandé aux gens autour de lui:
Aimez vous votre créateur ?
Rendez service à vos
semblables d'abord.
Le message de Dieu reçu
par Muhammad établissait
que les siens seraient tenus
responsables de leurs actions passées
après leur mort.
Bien que réticent à partager
cette expérience au début
une nouvelle révélation lui
commanda d'en parler en public
Il appelle donc les membres
de sa famille et leur dit
que me diriez vous si je
vous disait qu'une armée
se prépare à nous attaquer
depuis derrière la colline
Ils ont dit qu'ils le
croiraient. Il continua
que diriez vous si je vous disais
que je suis le messager de Dieu.
Ils lui répondent
que c'est ridicule
Comment as tu oser nous réunir pour ça ?
Il leur demande, donc aucun
de vous ne me supportera ?
Et une seule personne,
un enfant, Ali, son cousin
il se lève, et il dit,
moi je serai avec toi.
Les autres trouvent
la situation ridicule
Voici qui va suivre
ce prophète, un gamin
Imaginez la chose, vous
avez un homme quarantenaire
il ne sait ni lire ni
écrire et n'est pas riche
il est orphelin, certes il
vient d'une tribu influente
mais il travaille pour une femme.
Et il prétend être un prophète
Dieu m'a parlé.
Ca ne peut pas marcher.
La révélation Divine apportée par
Muhammad à ses compatriotes de la Mecque
était accompagné
d'un avertissement clair
à propos de leur
société matérialiste.
Il venait avertir les gens de la
Mecque et des campagnes alentours
et sa propre tribu des Quraich
que si ils ne se
réunissaient pas pour édifier
une société plus
juste et plus décente
en restaurant les valeurs tribales
de prendre soin des pauvres
des orphelins, des veuves, des opprimés
il y aurait une grande catastrophe.
Les Arabes ne croyaient
pas à la vie après la mort
Pour eux la vie se finissait à la
mort et il n'y avait point de résurrection
pas de retour, pas
de réincarnation
Maintenant Muhammad leur dit, vous
vous rappelez de ce Dieu dont on a parlé ?
A votre mort vous ne
disaparaîtrez pas simplement
Vous devrez vous
justifier devant ce Dieu
pour les bonnes et les mauvaises actions
Il apportait des notions morales,
éthiques et sociales à sa tribu
L'idée qu'on est tous dans le même bateau
face à Dieu, qu'on doit bien se traîter
faire preuve de compassion,
d'équité et de justice
La révélation reçue par Muhammad
sur la montagne de lumière
était la première d'une
série qu'il allait recevoir
pour le reste de sa vie.
La révélation ne vient pas d'un coup
Elle ne descend pas du
ciel en mode "voici le livre"
Maintenant va et prêche aux gens
Elle descend progressivement
Elle descend alors que
les événements arrivent
Elle donne une explication,
et surtout elle descend à un
rythme qu'il est capable de suivre
Car l'idée est que cette
chose est si massive
Elle est si énorme
qu'il est impossible de
tout lui donner d'un coup
Il va falloir du temps
Il disait n'avoir jamais eu de révélation
qui ne lui avait pas fait sentir
comme son âme se déchirer
Il pouvait être assis, à cheval
il pouvait marcher, il pouvait
être en train de discuter
D'un coup il était saisi
par le Divin message
Il sentait un grand
poids descendre sur lui
Il transpirerait beaucoup,
même si il faisait froid
Parfois il décrit la chose
comme le son d'une cloche
Et il ajouta que ceci était le plus dur
à supporter, ce n'étaient pas les mots
Mais le fait qu'il lui fallait écouter très
intensément pour capter le sens des mots
de cette communication
Divine qui passait par lui
Après avoir reçu chaque révélation,
il irait la professer
aux gens autour de lui
qui la transmettraient
à la communauté.
Lorsque le prophète,
incapable de lire ou d'écrire
commença à révéler
les versets du Coran
il acquis de la crédibilité
à cause de la nature même
des mots qu'ils contenaient
Les gens y regarderaient
de plus près et diraient
ces mots ne peuvent être le travail
d'un Homme. Il n'a pas pu tout inventer.
Le Coran présente une
énonciation extraordinairement belle
Ce n'est pas traduisible
mais l'Arabe utilisé est extraordinaire
Lorsque les premiers
musulmans entendirent le Coran
beaucoup d'entre eux se mirent directement
à accepter le message du Prophète
Pas forcément pour le contenu
mais du fait de la beauté des versets
La révélation arrivait
dans une société
où certaines personnes étaient
des mémorisateurs professionnels
Ils entendaient une chose une
fois et ensuite pouvaient la répéter
Les paroles de Muhammad
ont ainsi pu être préservées
immédiatement dans la
mémoire des mémorisateurs
et dans celle de ceux
capables de prendre des notes.
Le corpus que nous
appelons aujourd'hui le Coran
représente un ensemble
complet de ces versets
que Muhammad a prononcé lorsqu'il
disait qu'ils étaient la révélation Divine
Tout ce qu'on a sur le prophète,
et tout ce que l'on a de la
révélation Divine, ce sont des mots
Nous avons aucune image.
Nous avons aucune statue.
Tout ce qui nous reste, ce sont les mots.
A partir de ces mots,
via l'art de la calligraphie
nous pouvons les rendre
resplendissants, et plus accessibles
Pour Mohamed Zakariya,
les mots sont à la base d'un art.
Pour prévenir l'idôlaterie
Muhammad interdit la création
d'images de lui ou des autres prophètes
Ainsi la calligraphie devint
l'art le plus poussé de l'Islam.
Parmi les textes sacrés réalisés
par Zakariya se trouve la Hilye (حلية )
une description du
prophète par les mots.
Elle nous vient d'Ali, qui, quand on lui
demandait de décrire le prophète, disait:
Son visage était ni fin, ni rond
mais il était
quelque peu arrondi.
Quand il regardait quelqu'un
il le regardait avec son visage
tourné parfaitement vers lui.
Tout ceux qui le voyaient
étaient sans le vouloir, ébahis
et quiconque partageait
sa compagnie, l'appréciait
Tout ceux qui le décrivaient disaient:
'Jamais avant de le croiser
n'ais-je vu quelqu'un comme lui'
Que la paix soit sur lui
Voici la Hilye la plus connue.
Elle décrit si bien les
qualités de la personne
que l'on peut presque la voir
de nos yeux, on la visualise
Je vois ça comme avoir un petit
post-it sur le prophète à
côté de moi, pour le regarder
et se rappeler de lui
de temps en temps.
Bien sûr, il n'est pas
avec nous, mais la hilye
elle le rapproche,
rapproche sa présence
Muhammad a toujours insisté sur le
fait qu'il n'était pas une figure Divine
et s'est efforcé de prévenir ses
disciples de ne pas faire de lui
ce que les Chrétiens avaient fait de Jesus,
de le mettre sur un pied d'estal et dire
qu'il est Dieu ou au
moins d'essence Divine
Il n'était pas Divin, c'était un humain ordinaire,
et les musulmans ont pris ça très au sérieux
Mais ce qu'ils disent est que
Muhammad est l'homme idéal.
Que si l'on regarde sa vie
on peut voir comment l'on
peut se rendre pleinement à Dieu
"L'enseignement de Muhammad
commença à attirer des disciples"
surtout parmi les opprimés
de la société Mecquoise.
Ce sont les gens qui n'ont
plus rien à perdre et tout à gagner
Ce sont eux qui
répondent à l'appel
Beaucoup des disciples
sont les pauvres, les esclaves,
les femmes sans protection.
La nouvelle se répand parmis
les déshérités de la Mecque
Le prophète Muhammad
a remarqué qu'il
vivait dans une société qui
ne respectait pas les femmes.
Elles étaient vues comme
étant des personnes inférieures
un objet, ou une possession
qui appartient à l'homme.
Et celà dérangeait le prophète.
Très tôt dans sa vie prophétique, le prophète
dénonça l'infanticide des bébés filles
Des révélations plus tard allaient donner
aux femmes des droits dans le mariage
le droit de divorcer, une
garantie de leur droit à l'héritage
Il est bien sur anachronique et
absurde de considérer le prophète
comme un féministe
au sens du 21e siècle.
Il en reste que ce qu'il a fait pour les
femmes, dans son contexte, est impressionant.
Même si la majorité des femmes dans
l'Arabie pré-Islamique étaient des objets
La femme de Muhammad,
Khadija, était riche et influente.
Il y a cette idée que les femmes avant
l'Islam étaient vues comme du bêtail
qu'elles n'avaient aucun droits
Et je pense que pour de nombreuses
femmes, c'était le cas, mais
à un certain niveau de la société,
celui de Khadija par exemple
ce n'était pas le cas.
Khadija est une source d'instpiration car
malgré la société masculine dans
laquelle elle vivait, elle travaillait.
Il y a donc des parallèles que les femmes
actuelles peuvent faire, en suivant son exemple
J'ai grandi dans le
Cachemire (Pakistan)
which is in the foothills
of the Himalayas, northern India.
And I came to America when
I was 15 years old.
As I started becoming part and
parcel of this culture and society
I gravitated towards just wanting
to be like everybody else.
And tended to stray away
from my own faith.
And for awhile there
I went through some very
dark stages in my life
where I wanted nothing
to do with my faith
and almost just walked away
from my faith.
As I got older
I recognized that there was
this very empty hole inside of me.
So I started searching
for God in all kinds of places.
You know Rumi has this beautiful
story where he says
I looked for God, I went to a temple,
and I didn't find him there.
Then I went to a church and
I didn't find him there.
And then I went to a mosque and
"And then finally I looked
in my heart and there he was. "
The challenges that I faced in my life
are the very same challenges
that a lot of young girls are facing.
And, when they come to me
with their questions
I feel like a person who has already
traveled the road.
I dispense advice to them
from real experience as to how
I would have dealt with something.
I've noticed how when it comes to women
we are only supposed to marry Muslim men.
Uh, why is that now?
Especially because the Quran says that
believing men and women should marry
believing men and women, it doesn't
point out that men can marry
such and women can't.
I've heard plenty of people say that
in fact that's an interpretation.
Some of the issues are deeply personal
ah issues with gender relations
like dating and ah marriage.
And other issues have to do with
you know certain Islamic law and how
to reconcile with some of those things.
I want to exchange with her. See?
Her's is prettier
And these are all sticky
wickets as we say.
The fact that I've walked
the walk helps a little bit
for me to dispense advice to these people.
In Mecca,
opposition to Muhammad was growing.
His message of monotheism and
his campaign against idolatry
threatened the lucrative trade that
fueled the Meccan economy.
The business of Mecca is
to draw pilgrims to Mecca.
They want to make money.
And the way they draw pilgrims to Mecca is,
people come visit their gods.
Well, here's somebody who is saying,
these gods, they are not real.
They're stones, they're rocks.
You're wasting your time.
Now, that message has economic
implications to the Quraysh.
They are worried.
This, this man is going
to undermine our business.
In the tribal system Muhammad was
protected by his uncle, Abu Talib
so the Meccans went to Abu Talib and
asked him to turn Muhammad over to them.
Abu Talib was in a difficult position.
He was not a Muslim.
But it went against the grain
for him to simply hand
over his beloved nephew
to these people who would
kill him with impunity.
So he took Muhammad to one side and
said look don't do this.
Don't do this to us.
Can't you just keep quiet?
And at that point the Prophet says
if they put the sun in my right
hand and the moon in my left hand
I will not stop preaching
what I am preaching
until this message is conveyed or
I die conveying it.
And this is what he tells his uncle and
at that point he begins to weep.
And his Uncle looks at him and
realizes the depth of the conviction
of this man and he says say whatever
you want, you have my protection.
One of the things that
the prophet Muhammad S.A.W. taught us
was that it is our duty
to try to correct injustices in the world.
If you see something wrong,
change it with your hands.
If you're not able to,
then speak out against it.
If you're not able to do that,
then feel bad about it in your heart.
But that is the weakest form of faith.
Wherever possible the Muslim
should try to take action.
And not let an injustice go by
without calling it what it is,
and asking for change.
What do we have?
The book's prepared for the week.
Dealing with change is part of
Jameel Johnson's job.
As Chief-of-Staff for
Congressman Gregory Meeks of New York
he manages the congressman's schedule,
and briefs him on policy issues.
The biggest problem with the bill
is that there's the issue
of discrimination using federal funds.
Because it's not like a private plan.
So you're telling me that
you recommend a no vote.
I'm recommending a no vote.
As we had said in the beginning
I'm gonna give you the technical
part and what I think the issue is
you take care of the politics.
- Good deal...
- What else do we have?
My goal is not necessarily
to simply seek votes or
campaign money or to be accepted
as a part of the game.
As Muslims we must seek justice,
so what I try to do is educate.
In many cases the best thing
that you are able to do
with that kind of education
is decrease prejudice
and increase understanding.
If I practice my Islam on the job
and do that without trying to interfere
with anyone else's practice,
whether they be religious or otherwise
then I make it easier for the next
Muslim that comes on board.
Especially also if I do a good job
because then some of the prejudice,
some of the misunderstanding goes away.
Johnson coordinates the Friday
prayer service, or Jumah, on Capitol Hill.
It's grown since we started it,
it used to be sometimes 3, 5, 10 of us.
Now there can be up to 40, 50 people.
We're...
busting out of the room that we're in.
It's kind of a re-energizing
kind of refilling our fuel tank
with faith again for the rest of the week.
The image of the messenger
that gives us an example of somebody
who is extremely successful
as a head of state nevertheless he never
had to compromise his integrity.
One of the most important
things for a Muslim
is remaining constantly
in remembrance of Allah.
What we are commanded to do is that
we make, formal prayer 5 times a day.
Because when you live in a society
that constantly gives
you acceptance and praise
because of material things or achievement
we need that constant remembrance of Allah
in order to bring us back to the right path.
As some say, keeping our eyes on the prize.
And prayer is that remembrance.
Even though Islam isn't
the biggest faith in America
even though it sometimes is ridiculed
the fact of the matter is
that I can practice
I can make my five prayers a day.
It was much harder
for the Messenger of Allah S.A. W and
his companions to do this.
The first Muslims faced
a torrent of ridicule
and abuse when they practiced
Islam in public.
Attacked by crowds throwing stones
they retreated to the surrounding
mountains to pray in secret.
Many pagan families split apart
when their children converted to Islam.
Finally, the leaders of Muhammad's tribe,
the Quraysh
decided that Harassment alone
would not be enough to stop him.
The Quraysh, they see it as
our honor is being threatened
we need to deal with this.
This is the point where they begin
to really increase their persecution
they start sanctions
on the house of Beni Hashim,
which is the sub-clan of the
Prophet Muhammad.
They begin to prevent them from trading,
from transacting.
And that meant that basically
they were being starved out.
They couldn't buy food,
they couldn't do business.
Abu Talib ah was ruined by this.
The Hashim lived in one street and Muhammad
and Khadija and the children
moved into this street.
And this became a little Muslim ghetto.
And this leads to real hardship.
There's a period of time where
according to the tradition
they're actually eating
from the leaves of trees.
Famine destroyed
the fortunes of Muhammad's
protector, Abu Talib,
and his follower Abu Bakr.
The survival of both the clan and
Islam were in jeopardy.
But for Muhammad the damage
hit even closer to home.
Khadija, Muhammad's beloved wife, uh
perhaps weakened by the privations,
actually died.
And that was just
a crippling blow for him.
Left him feeling alone and
vulnerable and weak.
He would miss her all his life,
I think.
Then the catastrophe happened
that Abu Talib died.
Perhaps himself weakened
by the deprivation in food.
Now without Abu Talib
Muhammad was fair game for assassination.
And there's a terrible moment where
he utters this heart breaking prayer
saying oh my god I have no other
protector but you, Allah.
And how was he going to move forward?
He'd done what Allah had told him to do.
He had proclaimed this message and
all that he seemed to have done was
stir up hostility and hatred.
Um and split his tribe down the middle
this wasn't improving matters.
He must have felt an almost,
a sort of a dark night of the soul.
He is at the low point of his mission.
He's been almost 13 years now in Mecca and
the results are not,
they are not impressive.
But at this point, at this low ebb
he is now being prepared
for the most extraordinary
mystical experience
of his prophetic life
and that is what is known
as the night ascension.
The story goes that one night
he was sleeping near the Ka'aba
and he was woken from sleep by Gabriel
who mounted him on a Buraq
a magical stead
and they flew from Mecca to Jerusalem.
And then he began an ascent.
Up through the seven heavens
to the divine throne
at every stage of the heavens
he meets various prophets of the past.
He meets Abraham, he meets Jesus,
and John the Baptist.
He meets Moses
and finally he enters into
the divine presence and there
the sources are silent
because when you enter
into the presence of God
you have gone beyond words.
And he receives from God,
the highest form of knowledge and truth
and many injunctions of the religion
itself including the final form
of the daily prayers
Now all of this took place
in a time beyond time.
That's why some sources say
that as the door was
swinging when he left,
it was still swinging when he came back.
For later Muslims this also
meant that the departure point
that is Jerusalem, the Dome of the Rock,
became also important.
Many Muslims say that there are
three holy cities in Islam:
Mecca, and Medina, the City of the Prophet,
and Jerusalem.
When he comes back somebody asks him
what have you been doing, he says
I went to Jerusalem last night
and this man says,
you went to Jerusalem last night?
Are you willing to say that publicly?
So they assemble this group and
they tell him, describe for us
Jerusalem and he begins
to describe it in very exact detail.
And they're shocked.
They don't what to make of this now.
The story of the Night Journey not
only incited Muhammad's enemies.
It caused doubt even among
some of his followers.
This is something that
they hadn't really expected.
A journey that takes them
a month to be made
in an evening and to come back.
What Abu Bakr says is listen
I believe that he's getting
messages from God.
That is certainly more extraordinary
than making a Night Journey to Jerusalem.
As Muhammad's relationship with
the Meccans continued to deteriorate
his enemies decided that the time
had come to eliminate him.
And they decide to get
a youth from each clan.
They all come together and they're going
to strike him with one blow together.
So, the blood is distributed
amongst all the clans.
Under cover of darkness the assassins
surrounded Muhammad's home.
Inside a covered figure lay asleep.
As dawn broke, they prepared to strike.
But Muhammad had been
forewarned of the plot.
He asked his cousin Ali
whom he knew the Quraysh would not harm,
to take his place.
By the time the assassins
burst into his home
Muhammad and his companion Abu Bakr
had escaped into the desert.
With the Meccans in hot pursuit
they set out on a circuitous
route to the oasis
settlement of Yathrib,
250 miles to the north.
For several months,
Muhammad had been sending
his followers there for refuge.
Now, he was about to join them.
Yathrib was quite different from Mecca.
It was an agricultural settlement.
People grew dates and they had
farms and there were a number
of clans and tribes living
together in the settlement.
The settlement was engulfed
in tribal warfare of the worst kind.
It was an example of where the whole
system in Arabia was beginning
to break down.
One killing led to another and nobody
could seem to find a solution.
Nobody, that is,
until the clans of Yathrib
heard about the trustworthy Muhammad.
Hoping he could unify its warring factions
which included two major pagan
tribes and their Jewish allies
a delegation from Yathrib
had taken the dramatic step
of inviting Muhammad
to move to their settlement.
The deal is that he will serve
as their binding arbitrator
that is both sides
to the conflict have agreed
already that they will accept
the arbitration of Muhammad
whatever it would be.
The people of Yathrib vowed
that they would take
the Muslims on board as honorary
tribesmen, they would be their protectors.
Anyone who hurt the Muslims,
they would retaliate.
And the Muslims agreed to do the same.
This move from your tribe
to join up with people who were of no kin
to you at all was absolutely unheard of.
Muhammad was really going off
into the wilderness here
he was breaking every tie.
Doing something utterly
shocking and novel.
When Prophet Muhammad was leaving
he stood up on a hill
and he was looking on Mecca
and his tears were coming
down out of his eyes.
And he talked to Mecca and he said
God knows that I love you Mecca
so much, but it is your people
who are chasing me out.
In Yathrib, Muhammad's followers
anxiously awaited the Prophet's arrival.
Had the man they hoped would
save them been able to save himself?
Had the Meccans captured or
even killed him?
When Muhammad finally reached
the outskirts of the city
his relieved followers rushed to greet him
with a song Muslims around
the world still sing 1400 years later.
Oh the wise moon rose over us
from the valley of Wadan.
And we always do show gratefulness
where the call is to Allah.
Muhammad's arrival marked
the beginning of a dramatic
new chapter in the history of Islam.
For the first time
he would be the leader
of a sovereign community
based on Islamic law.
Yathrib would henceforth
become known as Medina.
Muhammad arrives in Medina as
somebody who was escaping danger.
He's been invited there but
he doesn't know what to expect...
So at each stage of his life,
there's a new challenge
and obviously,
new fears and new doubts.
And so, he started thinking
in terms of policy.
In terms of strategy.
In terms of tactics.
And that's what ultimately
made him into a statesman.
Because that's what statesmen do.
Now unlike Jesus, or the Buddha
who seem to have been purely
spiritual leaders
with no temporal responsibilities whatever
MUHAMMAD found himself now head of state.
Having transferred the Muslim families
from MECCA to Medina.
He now had to make sure
they could survive there.
The survival of the fledgling
community depended on
its ability to defend itself
against attacks from Mecca.
To respond to this possibility
Muhammad developed
a novel political solution.
He essentially establishes
a pact, an agreement
sometimes it's called
the Constitution Of Medina.
Whether you were a Pagan or a Muslim
or a member of the Jewish tribes or
any other tribes in Medina
you had to sign on to this pact.
And the pact established that
if there were ever an attack
on Medina from the outside
all the inhabitants of the town
of would be responsible
to defend the city.
This way, Muhammad really developed
a revolutionary idea
which was transcend
your tribal responsibilities
your petty particularism
and begin to think in larger terms,
as a entire community.
Now this was a very fearful terrifying
time for Muslims but nevertheless
it was seen as a creative time when
faith was at its strongest.
It's a creative act for Muslims
to look back at the
Muslim community in Medina and
try to apply the
ideals to their own society
so that they can
reproduce something of the Prophet's
original spirit.
I came here to this country and
I came with a feeling that
I left back in my original country
in Iraq many memories
many painful memories
one of them that my grandfather as well as
13 members of all my family
were persecuted and imprisoned
by the dictator Saddam Hussein.
That reminds me of the agony and pain
many early immigrants went through
when they came to Medina.
Like many other Muslims who have fled
persecution in their native countries
Imam Hassan Qazwini, was drawn to America
by the promise of religious freedom and
economic opportunity.
He emigrated to Dearborn Michigan
a community that boasts the highest
per capita concentration of Muslims
in the United States
where people are almost as likely
to speak Arabic as English.
Hijra, migration,
it has a shining aspect for me.
As well as for the Prophet and his
companions who came with him
from Mecca to Medina.
And that shining aspect was the freedom
religious freedom that they faced in Medina.
Muslims here in America, they feel
they are more free in practicing
their religion than many
other Muslim countries.
In many ways this whole immigration
process from Mecca to Medina very much
parallels what's happened in my own city
here in Dearborn, in our own backyard.
And I see it play out in
the hospital where I work.
Najah Bazzy is a nurse
at Dearborn's Oakwood Hospital.
She conducts training sessions
to help bridge
the gap of understanding between
the hospital staff
and their Muslim patients,
many of whom are immigrants.
I know you're all nurses, and I know
that you're in this profession,
just as I am, to serve, to do a good job.
But it's real easy for us to get
caught up in our own baggage.
We're all human and we all have
a certain set of preconceived notions
just as you walk through
the door and you saw me
for the first time, just as you
might have seen Alijah.
In the sensitivity training inevitably,
they know very little about the faith of Islam.
They think that the faith of Islam is
a very maybe terroristic, militant, barbaric
spread by the sword faith.
And so when they have a Muslim
up there talking about
patient rights, dignity,
issues around health
and illness, all of a sudden you see
all of these stereotypes that people
have as part of, you know, the baggage
as we grow up, just kind of fall.
When you transcend culture,
you arrive at a universal place
where our humanness is all the same.
You grieve the same.
We all cry when someone we love dies.
When we deliver, those of us who deliver,
we all experience labor.
Something happened in Dearborn that further
established a need for this kind of work
and that was a huge immigration process
as a result of the Gulf War.
As a critical care nurse, Najah Bazzy
often has to counsel patients with terminal
illnesses, like this Iraqi immigrant who
has just been diagnosed with uterine cancer.
I said to her what do you think you have?
And she said I have an infection in
the uterus and they took it out.
Maybe she's not hearing it the first time,
maybe she doesn't need to hear it.
Maybe she can't hear it.
They're just not saying
the "C" word at all.
They're not using that word with her.
And they want to just
maintain hope, and uh...
- just want to treat it
delicately, okay? - Okay. - Alright.
Ok.. Thanks
Salaam Alaykum
These are families immigrating
from a way of life.
And mostly because they
have been torn by war.
And so they get here and
the helpers are here.
And it's quite obligatory
to be that helper.
When Muhammad arrived in Medina,
he made it clear that helping
immigrants would be one of the
cornerstones of the new Islamic society.
This is his message, spread peace,
feed people food, and
do some devotional practice and you
will enter paradise without any trouble.
Two-thirds of that message
is about other people.
The secret of Medina is it's
a place where human beings are
going to attempt to live up to
the ideal of the Islamic tradition.
Part of the arrangement was that
the people of Medina agreed
that they would provide housing and
support for the immigrants as they came in.
And very often they were
even paired so that
certain people had direct responsibility
for specific people from Mecca.
And that did not take place in 24 hours.
It came step by step, step by step, and
within a few months, you now had two groups
the Helpers, so called,
El Ansar, that is, those
Medinan Arabs who had become
Muslims, and the Meccans
who had become Muslims before them.
And in this way, for the first time, he created
the Islamic Ummah, that is, the Islamic people.
That bond which transcends
all other bonds.
He said to these people,
these are now your neighbors
these are your brothers and sisters.
He establishes that sense
of humanity, that Ummah.
We are all connected to one another,
we are all responsible for one another.
A couple of you guys
to carry to my car, ok?
There's a mosque in
the heart of Detroit and
it's run by an Imam who
started a soup kitchen
I want the kids to be able to see
that that's part of Muhammad's message.
- This is the exit right here.
- Hang on everybody it's a sharp turn.
Hajji is like not a good driver.
Listen, I'm a good driver.
This is the first test. If you can't
pass this test the rest of it's off.
The majority of the ones that come for
the soup kitchen are non-Muslim.
It's only about, maybe one or two people
that are Muslim that come for the soup kitchen.
And we let them know that it's a part
of who we are, as to why we're doing this.
It's a part of what God has commanded for the
Muslims, for a human being to be charitable.
I'm studying to be ordained as
a Catholic Deacon, so I had run into
Abdullah when he made a presentation
about Islam and uh...
I was really attracted
to the works of this mosque.
I was never aware that there was
an active part of Muslim faith life
that really reached out to the poor. I wasn't
even sure that it was part of your creed.
Abdullah went through misunder standings
that would commonly exist...
he started with the term Black Muslim.
What does that bring to mind?
And honestly it brought to mind certain
things that would make you fearful.
Certain kinds of maybe aggressive
behavior, nationalistic kinds of thinking
you know, as if we are going carve ourselves
off from the others and have no fellowship.
He said if I tell you what the
stereotypes are that I have of Catholics
when you listen to them,
you'll say oh those are
extreme examples,
those are not what we are about.
Dearborn is the place where
the early immigrants of
Arab, Lebanese and Middle Eastern
people came and settled down.
This country embraced them and
opened its door for them.
Yet they needed time to adjust and
go through that
difficulty they faced when
they came to this country.
It's two different societies,
two different cultures.
Najah and Ali Bazzy are raising
their family in the suburbs of Dearborn.
Their children are third
generation American Muslims.
We're trying to combine the best
of both worlds and giving
our kids the family values that
our parents teach and realize
that they live in, uh, you know,
a land in the United States
which has, you know, many opportunities
for our kids to prosper in.
- You still can't beat me.
- I'll beat you tonight.
- Can you shoot five and 0?
- I can shoot 5 and 0 from anywhere.
- 5 and 0 anywhere?
- Right now? Let's go.
Like many Dearborn families the Bazzy's
struggle daily to balance the
sometimes conflicting demands of their
faith and modern American society.
Their daughter Nadia,
has decided to wear the hijab
or head covering, that was first
worn by Muhammad's wives.
Many Muslim women still wear the hijab
as a sign of modesty and piety.
Well, we're gonna back you
one way or the other.
That's a given.
Our daughter came to us and said,
I made a decision.
And she's 16 now.
And she said, I've decided that
I want to wear hijab.
The last time when you put it on, right?
You made me take it off.
No, I didn't make you take it off.
I sort of persuade you thinking, try and bring
it out the other, end of the light of it, right?
And you resented me for that, correct?
Big time.
I just thought maybe if you
go through high school
and then put it on after
high school, that then
if then, at least at that point
in life, you'll
be able to see what you want
to do in life, and that.
Because you gotta understand something.
You know, you never know where you're
gonna be and where you're gonna go in life.
I mean, it's, sure,
this hijab is accepted in
our community here, and,
you know, you maybe do well.
And you end up being a doctor or a lawyer
whatever, you'll be doing
very well for yourself.
But look what just happened to you
when you went down to Tennessee.
I mean, here you have her driving a bus
and the state police trooper
wants to stop over, we've
got a whole bus full of people,
because he sees hijabs.
I think for Nadia, he probably
feels much like I feel.
There is great reverence for it,
and then there's that
that oh my gosh, I want to protect
my daughter from the world.
I don't want people to think
she's a terrorist.
I don't want people
to think she's oppressed.
I don't want people to think I'm her father,
I made her put that on her head.
All of those kinds of things
come into play.
I don't think Baba is, you know,
trying to hurt you here.
He's trying to show you a picture
of the real world, and
what you need to do is show him
a real picture of your world.
He's a father, he has some
legitimate concerns.
So my point is that you're
still the same Nadia.
Ali, maybe she's not done
talking to you.
You've talked to her.
Give her a few minutes and now
let her talk to you.
Do you know that I'm, that I'm doing
this for myself and for you?
Remember something. You're not doing it
for me. You're doing it for yourself and God.
All right?
You're the one who has to answer to God.
- So do you.
- I will answer to God. Don't worry about that.
I have my positives and my negatives in life
and I will answer to God, don't worry about it.
Baba, all that I do is a reflection of you.
You're in good shape, then.
You're in good shape, right?
So are we at peace?
I never knew we were at war
Muhammad also tells you that, you know
you should always give what's
best, uh, for your daughter.
And me as a father, I'm just trying
to give my daughter the opportunity.
To be able to see, uh, life from a wider
angle and a bigger perspective.
People would immigrate into different parts
of the country, but what was interesting is
that they would all manage to find their
way into Dearborn, a great many of them.
And the reason for that is because
the mosques were in place.
Dearborn's newest mosque will be
the largest in North America.
Like the first mosque in Medina, it is being
built with help from the entire community.
There's great feelings of ownership
to the mosque when the community builds it.
People are baking food.
Every year they contribute between
$50,000 to $100,000 to the income and
the operating costs of our mosque.
So, we have the building of this mosque,
kind of metaphorically
and the laying of the bricks and
this new foundation
with all these new immigrants in Dearborn.
And everybody brings their contribution.
Prophet Muhammad established
the first center in Medina
for Muslims and that was his mosque.
And it was not only a place where Muslims
go and do their prayer, or
offer their supplication, it was the center
for the entire community.
It was the headquarters of the Prophet.
He would become a judge and solve
problems among people inside the mosque.
So he receives delegations,
he would declare war or peace.
The mosque was serving multiple purposes
in the life of Prophet Muhammad.
It was at the mosque
that Muhammad discussed
a sweeping change in strategy
with his followers.
After years of exercising restraint
in the face of persecution by the Meccans
Muhammad received a clear new revelation
that marked a dramatic
departure from the past.
It gave the Muslims limited permission
to take up arms in self-defense.
The statesman was about
to become a general.
For 13 years, there's been no
sanction to fight.
Then a revelation comes that says
those who have been removed
unjustly from their homes, and
have been fought because
of their religious beliefs
are sanctioned to fight
to defend themselves.
Killing is always abhorrent,
the QURAN makes it very clear about that
and the QURAN says that it's always wrong
to start a war, to be an aggressor.
But persecution is worse than killing.
When people have been driven from their
homes, or deprived of their basic human rights
when an evil ideology comes
into the world, sometimes
regrettably, it may be necessary to fight
and sometimes lives will be lost.
Muhammad's first large military engagement
occurred near the town of Badr, when
313 Muslims set out to surprise a caravan
from Muhammad's own tribe, the Quraysh.
In a sense, the battle of Badr,
which became such a landmark
in Muslim history,
ah was a sort of mistake.
Ah, the Muslims had planned
a conventional raid but
the Meccans, when they heard
that this band of renegades
was attacking their great caravan
were so enraged they sent out
the whole army against them.
And the Muslims were convinced that
they were going to die.
He never wanted to fight the Meccans.
I mean, the Meccans are his people, uh,
his, his friends, his family.
He wants to co-opt them, he wants to make
them the key, if you will to the new
Islamic Ummah that he's trying to form,
so he doesn't want to go to war with them.
As he prepared to lead the Muslims
into battle, Muhammad took
the unprecedented step of establishing
clear rules of engagement for his army.
He makes it very clear to his soldiers
that if they have the right to use
force against the Qurayshy
that does not mean that they
will do the same thing
that has been done
in pre-Islamic wars.
In which women and children
could be killed
in which no prisoners could be taken,
no quarter given.
No, No.
He said Islam is a religion of law.
The Meccans had sent an army
of about 1,000 men.
As the army approached, Muhammad prepared
to make a stand near a well.
One of his soldiers suddenly
questioned his strategy
Has God revealed it to you? he asked,
"Or is it your own opinion?"
When Muhammad answered that he was
speaking as a man, not a prophet
the soldier suggested that they
stop at a larger well closer
to the enemy, so they could
deprive them of water.
Muhammad agreed at once.
The change in strategy proved decisive,
and the Muslims recorded a resounding triumph.
It was a victory that stunned the Muslims.
It seemed like a complete reversal,
like a miracle.
Almost a sort of revelation
of God in history.
A Furqan, they called it.
Something that separated
the just from the unjust.
After the battle, Muhammad received
a revelation claiming the victory for God.
The Muslims felt that angels
had been fighting alongside them.
The victory reaffirmed their
belief that God was on their side
and raised Muhammad's status higher still.
But his followers also knew that
the Meccans would seek violent retribution.
A year later, an army of 3,000 Meccans
returned to face 1,000 Muslims
in the battle of Uhud.
The resulting rout left the future
of Islam in mortal peril.
It was a horrible battle.
And the corpses of the Muslims were
mutilated by the Meccans.
And the Meccan women,
as was their wont
came out onto the battlefield and
danced around the corpses.
Sixty-five of Muhammad's soldiers
lost their lives in the battle
including a Rabbi who had
honored the Medina Pact
by fighting alongside Muhammad.
The families of the fallen Muslims
were now without protectors.
Then, Muhammad received a new revelation
allowing Muslim men to safeguard
these women and children
by taking as many as four wives, but
only if they could treat them equally.
That, in itself, in the context of Arabia,
was a bit of a restriction
because a man could have
unlimited number of wives
the context of the permission to polygamy
is to say who is going
to look after these women.
It was an act of faith, not an act
of lust that inspired men to take more wives.
So, it would be wrong to think
of the Prophet as basking
decadently in the garden of sensual
delights with his harem.
His harem was very much a matter of state
and sometimes his wives were
rather a mixed blessing.
Although Muhammad was monogamous
during Khadija's life, after her death
he eventually married a number of women
including one of the Uhud widows,
Umm Salama.
The reason for his marriages
were really political alliances.
It was a tribal society, and for Muhammad
to marry into another tribe and
take a wife just meant that there was
a bond being created with this tribe.
Among Muhammad's wives were the daughters
of his two closest allies
Abu Bakr and Umar.
Abu Bakr's daughter, Aisha, would become
one of the most influential
women in his life.
Aisha was very lively.
She was, uh, brilliant.
She was somebody that questioned the prophet.
She was not somebody in any way that
um took everything, she questioned him.
She said, what does that mean?
Uh, why did you do this,
why did you do that?
Um, she was somebody that really had a,
an incredibly active mind.
She memorized vast amounts of prophetic
traditions, and she's considered to be
actually, the transmitter of a large number
of, uh, traditions from the prophet Muhammad.
In the year that followed the battle
of Uhud, the Meccans girded themselves
for a final assault that they hoped would
finish off the Muslims once and for all.
They assembled one of the largest armies
ever seen in Arabia and marched on Medina.
But Muhammad hit upon a daring defense.
Muhammad has dug a trench around
the whole of the settlement.
And you have an almost comic scene
with the Meccan cavalry
galloping up to this trench, and pulling back
in horror, and saying what is this?
They've never seen anything so
unsporting in their lives.
This is something, they say,
the Arabs don't do.
It sounds comical but surrounded
by the powerful Meccan army
the Muslims were expecting all
to be killed, to a man, to a woman.
Stopped by the trench around Medina,
the Meccans laid siege
to the city and to the hundreds
of Muslim families trapped inside.
According to the Muslim sources,
in their determination
to defeat Muhammad,
the Meccans had recruited
as allies many Bedouin tribes
as well as the largest Jewish tribe
within Medina, the Bani Qurayzah.
For the Muslims,
this defection was the final blow
in a relationship that had been
strained from the beginning.
When Muhammad came to town
the organized Jewish community
did not accept his prophecy.
There were, according
to the Islamic sources
some individual Jews that did accept him
but for the most part the community
as a whole did not.
If the Jews would accept his
Prophethood, then he has
tremendous and complete
confirmation of his Prophethood.
But the Jews were so well respected that
when they rejected his prophethood
and they did it actively
they became a very serious political
threat to his very existence in Medina.
Despite the aid of the Bani Qurayzah
the Meccan siege could not break
through the Muslim defenses.
When the weather turned bad
and as the Bedouin tribes began
deserting the field of battle
the Meccans themselves
lost heart and departed
abandoning their Jewish allies to be
tried by the Muslims for the crime of treason.
Islamic sources believe that
the Jews did indeed
aid the enemy in trying
to defeat Muhammad.
This was absolutely against
the terms of the Media agreement.
The Jews and the Muslims decided
that they would choose
an arbitrator to determine what would
be the future of the Jews.
The person who was chosen was a man
who was mortally wounded
in the Battle of the Trench.
And so he determined that the women and
children of the Bani Qurayzah
would be taken as slaves to the Muslims,
and the men would be killed.
The Prophet agreed with this judgement.
When he judged he said
that you have judged according
to God and his messenger.
And then, uh, approximately 700 men
uh, were killed. Uh, they were executed.
So, this definitely occurred.
All that can be said is that,
this cannot be seen as anti-Semitism, per se.
MUHAMMAD had nothing against the Jewish
people per se, or the Jewish religion.
The QURAN continues to tell Muslims
to honor the People of the Book.
And to honor their religion as authentic.
And the Jewish tribes who had not rebelled
who had not given help to the MECCANS
continued to live in MEDINA,
completely unmolested.
MUHAMMAD was not trying to exterminate Jews.
He was trying to get rid of very
dangerous internal enemies.
It's unfortunate that many historians and
particularly in contemporary times
both on the Jewish and on the Muslim
side, uh, have transformed this.
On the Jewish side, they have
used that as a way of saying
well, you see, the Muslims hate
the Jews and they kill them.
And, and on the Muslim side, it says
well, you see, the Jews are full of
treachery and can't be trusted.
Both are wrong.
When the other tribes of the peninsula
saw the impotence of Mecca
with all its power and might
against this little community
they began to switch allegiance and
see that Muhammad was the coming man.
Now once that happened,
once the tide had been turned
after the battle of the trench, and
the Muslims were no longer subject
to the fear of extermination
Muhammad stopped the fighting.
The Prophet Muhammad
received a few people
militants who just arrived
from one of the battles that
they came back from and,
they felt so important that
we finished this job fighting
with the enemies of Islam.
And the Prophet smiled and he said
let me tell you something.
You finished the minor Jihad and now
you have the bigger Jihad ahead of you.
And they were stunned.
They thought that they just
finished the biggest achievement
in their life by being willing
to sacrifice their own life.
And the Prophet explained
that the biggest Jihad
is struggle against your own
desires and limitations.
Jihad does not mean holy war, primarily.
The word means effort, striving.
And it's always a hard struggle to put
the word of God into practice.
When the Quran talks about struggling or
they're not talking always
about fighting a holy war
they're talking about this immense
struggle to implement
a divine imperative in the flawed and
tragic conditions of daily life.
Fighting might sometimes have
to be done as part of the Jihad
but it is by no means the major imperative.
I remember a quotation from Jesus,
peace be upon him(PBUH)
who says that the first
step in the reformation
journey is to start with your own self.
If you want to reform the society
you have to reform yourself first.
And that was basically the meaning of Jihad.
The Prophet put that emphasis
on inner development.
Jihad, the constant struggle with yourself,
to improve yourself and perfect your intent.
That you do things only for the sake of God.
The most excellent Jihad, Holy struggle,
is the struggle to control your ego, the self.
For a long time I was deathly afraid
of speaking in public, of giving speeches.
And I saw that and I, well, this my Jihad,
I've gotta overcome this fear.
If I'm gonna help people, it's gonna be
necessary for me to talk in public.
To be able just to speak out.
And going back to 1987 I had
become active as far as writing
articles for papers to have
fire safe cigarette legislation enacted.
Cigarettes are the largest cause
of fire fatalities in the nation.
So, I began writing and because
of my position I could speak from
the authority as a fire fighter and,
and now a Supervising Fire Marshal.
Going back to if you save one life
it's like you saved all humanity.
Well I feel I was part of an effort
to save thousands of lives each year because
of this legislation that
we passed in New York State.
Jihad is misused.
There is absolutely nothing in Islam
that justifies, uh, the claim of
Osama bin Laden, Al Qaeda or other
similar groups to kill innocent civilians.
That is unequivocally a crime
under Islamic law.
Acts of terror violence that have
occurred in the name of Islam
are not only wrong,
they are contrary to Islam.
September 11th, I hooked up with
two other fire marshals.
We found a place to park near the bridge,
about several inches of soot.
If it had been white and colder out,
you would have sworn it was snow.
We came over the Brooklyn Bridge, uh
it was just like something out of a movie.
It was very quiet, you know, that muffled
sound that you have during a blizzard
you know, where you can't hear your feet
hitting the ground, it's just very muffled
very quiet.
So we put on our turn out gear and
we started heading over there.
And it's just, I think
I could speak for all of
we were just all in a state
of shock and disbelief.
I just felt, oh, in the back of my head,
please don't be Muslims doing this.
And I just felt ah, I just felt sick.
We could see this fragment of the
World Trade Center sticking up
almost like a lopsided crown.
Then we started walking
down one way and
we saw some fire fighters, you know
dazed and shell shocked,
saying don't go down there
there's still more collapses happening.
I mean, we were dying to go
out there and do something.
And, you know, we're figuring that
some of the brothers or even
anyone, you know, people could still
be alive, trapped under the rubble.
But, we just, it was frustrating,
but, I mean
you have to understand that
they don't want to lose more people
on top of the people who are lost already.
This is just, I mean, it was just out and
out madness what they did.
The Prophet himself in the course
of the circumstances engaged in battle
in warfare, but he had a certain code
of conduct that he followed.
So, you have to separate fanaticism,
which every religion has
from the reality and the truth
of that religion.
These are fanatics who have lost
sight of what the purpose of religion is and
they're acting, you know, on their own.
What hurt me probably most of all,
out of the World Trade Center attack
was that here is a religion that
I entered because of the universality.
And the tolerance that
is throughout the book and
throughout the sayings of Prophet Muhammad.
Yet, these people who did that and
were behind it and planned it
were just so intolerant and
so disregarding of their own tenets
that they could do something so horrific and
kill people in such a horrible
***Missing***
September 11th,
underscored the need to have dialogue
with non-Muslims and other faiths
to understand each other and to try to resolve
these hot spots that fester and cause
this type of hatred.
Uh, the death and destruction
in New York City
that was caused by this terrible,
terrible act in the name of Islam
has propelled the Muslim community in
New York to respond in many different ways.
And one of the ways that I want to respond
is the way the Prophet would have responded.
To just talk about the humanity
which we all belong to.
Since September 11 Muslims
have gone to churches
to synagogues,
to schools to explain our faith.
However, people still kept asking
where are the Muslims and why aren't
they doing something about it.
So I started thinking about this and I said,
what is it that we are not doing right?
Maybe we need to respond
in a more gentle way.
So I looked around for the mildest
people in our community.
The artists in our community.
And the first person
I called was Mohamed Zakariya.
Catastrophes have brought us here,
but not all is lost.
Uh, through our art,
we pick up all these broken pieces and
try to put them back together again and
make something that's gonna work.
Revenge, suicide bombing, things of that
kind they have no place in Islam.
They must never have
a place in Islam, never.
Never.
Islam is really a soft thing,
it's not a hard thing
And so we have to approach it with
softness, and be soft to each other.
(Arabic) the Prophet said.
Make it easy and not difficult.
So we should put away
all those angry words
the harsh, the strident rhetoric that
that we have been dealing with
for all these years that we've suffered
through this sweet religion
with this beastly stuff.
And come out into the light,
and be bright.
Be bright in America.
And look in the mirror,
that's what we have to do.
Salaam Alaykum
This piece is the golden rule of Islam.
It is the basis of the relations
between people
It means that there is no harming
of other people in Islam
and no returning or retaliating
harm for harm.
And so that's why I did it.
To respond through the sayings
of Muhammad the man.
By the year 628,
the battles that had occupied
the Muslims for the preceding
four years had come to an end.
Once the Muslims were no longer fearing
the threat of total extermination
MUHAMMAD knew that the time
for fighting had stopped.
And it was now time to make
an extraordinary initiantive
a peaceful, nonviolent initiative.
He astonished the whole Muslim community
and the whole community
of Yathrib by announcing that
he was going to go on the Hajj pilgrimage
Dangerous as it was,
an enormously risky as it was
about a thousand Muslims
volunteered to go with MUHAMMAD.
All the rites were fulfilled to the letter.
The camels all decked in
their special sacrificial garments.
The men all in their white garb.
The Muslims set out
on the perilous trip to Mecca
crossing the vast desert without
any arms to defend themselves.
When they reached Hudaybiyah,
just outside the sacred area around Mecca
where violence was forbidden
Muhammad surprised his followers not
to enter, but to sit and wait.
He then sent an emissary to Mecca seeking
permission to complete the pilgrimage.
MUHAMMAD knew of course,
that he was putting the
people of MECCA into a really
impossible position.
Because if they forbade Arabs, to enter
the city and perform the rights of the Ka'aba
they would be abusing their position
as guardians of the holy places.
The MECCANS themselves did not
know what to do.
When the emissary did not return quickly,
the Muslims feared the worst.
But Muhammad's gambit paid off.
The Meccans offered to negotiate a treaty.
With tensions running high
Muhammad began dictating its first
line by stating his own name.
Ali was taking down the notes
with the MECCAN negotiator at his side
and when MUHAMMAD began to saying
the Prophet of God, the MECCAN saids,
I don't believe you are the Prophet of God
I can't sign to that.
So he said fine, Muhammad,
Son Of Abdullah.
And many of the Muslims felt that
this was a major insult.
The Muslims, sitting around Hudaybiyah
watched this in utter dismay.
There was almost a mutiny.
A thousand pilgrims stood,
refusing to accept this.
MUHAMMAD went back into his tent
where he had his wife, Umm Salama.
And he said to her, what shall I do?
And she gave him some excellent advice
part of the ritual of the HAJJ
was that you sacrificed a camel.
And he went out and
he sacrificed one of the camels
and somehow some kind of necessary
tension was released.
The ritual sacrifice of an animal
traditionally marked the end of the pilgrimage.
Grudgingly, the Muslims considered
the pilgrimage complete
and headed back to Medina.
Muhammad had compromised on every
major point in the treaty.
But he had won the most
significant concession.
In return for postponing their
entry into Mecca for a year
the Muslims had secured
ten years of peace
and official recognition
as a political entity.
Muhammad had proved himself as capable
a diplomat as he was a religious leader.
There was wisdom in the treaty
because one of the things that
was promised to the Muslims
was protection as they moved
throughout Arabia.
That they would not be harmed and
they could move freely.
And what was gained most greatly from that
was the dauwa, the teaching of al-Islam.
On the way back to Medina,
Muhammad told a companion, Umar
I have received a revelation which is dearer
to me than anything else beneath the sun.
it said, "Surely",
"We have given you a clear victory. "
Then more and more and more
people came to Islam
more and more people turned to MUHAMMAD.
It sent out a huge signal of strength.
Strength of purpose, utter courage, utter
panache, and utter wisdom that, of course
you could go on to fight
of course he could have gone on being
the prophet with the sword
but there are times when
to make peace is more daring
more creative, and more enduring.
One year after signing
the Hudaybiyah treaty,
Muhammad led his followers on
a new pilgrimage to Mecca.
After years of rejection,
persecution, and humiliation
this was truly a moment of triumph.
The first pilgrimage of the Muslims
after Hudaybiyah must have been
an extraordinary event for everybody.
Because the MECCANS couldn't bear it.
They decamped and went and sat up in
the hills and mountains outside the city, and
watched this procession, huge procession
of Muslims, and some of their confederates
coming on the HAJJ, and as it were,
taking possession of the city
crying out the pilgrim cry, here I am, oh,
God, here I come, in a huge cry.
Then came the moment Muhammad had waited
seven long years to achieve.
Muhammad sends Bilal, an African ex-slave
this lowest of the low
in the eyes of the Meccans
up on to the sacred shrine of the Ka'aba
what the Meccans regard as their shrine
to deliver the call to prayer.
And the hills around Mecca are granite.
They're set up for a sonorous voice.
And the call to prayer resonates
through the valley.
Bilal was proclaiming for all to hear,
there is one God and Muhammad is his Prophet.
It must have been an appalling moment
for the MECCANS.
But an extraordinary moment
of exhilaration for the Muslims.
Performing all the rites punctiliously
and then taking no advantage of this,
going back peacefully home.
But the peace between the Muslims and
the people of Mecca would not last.
By the end of the year, the Meccans
had broken the Treaty of Hudaybiyah
by attacking a clan allied with Muhammad.
In response, 10 days into
the holy month of Ramadan
Muhammad and a Muslim army of 10,000 men
set out to take Mecca by force.
The Prophet felt he was strong enough
to be able to conquer MECCA.
But as the army approached the city,
more and more leaders of the Quraysh
realized that they were not going to win,
and so many decided to join Islam.
The prophet entered the city
without resistance.
When he came into Mecca he came
in with his head bowed down.
He did not come in as, as,
as an arrogant conquering warrior.
He comes in humbled by a victory
that he sees is from God.
After circling the Ka'aba seven times
Muhammad destroyed each of the three
hundred sixty idols that surrounded it.
He then turned to the vanquished Meccans
who had sought refuge inside the shrine.
His own brethren, who had oppressed and
attacked the Muslims for so many years.
He says, if you were in my position right now,
what do you think you would do
and the Meccans are afraid
they're about to die.
And then he says, you are all pardoned.
He grants them all amnesty.
And this was unheard of in this culture,
unheard of in this society.
And very unexpected among the Meccans.
The religion that had begun
in ridicule and persecution
was now thriving throughout
the Arabian peninsula.
But shortly after returning to Medina,
Muhammad received a premonition of his death.
He told his daughter Fatima that
every year during Ramadan
the angel Gabriel recited the Quran
to him and asked him to repeat it.
This year Gabriel had asked Muhammad
to recite the Quran twice.
I cannot but think, Muhammad said,
that my time has come.
In February 632
Muhammad made what would be his final
pilgrimage to the city of his birth.
On his first pilgrimage, he had led
a few hundred Muslims back to Mecca.
This time, tens of thousands of believers
followed in his footsteps.
He arrives in Mecca
as the leader of the Muslim people now,
not as the enemy of the Meccans.
And they begin to perform
the rites of the pilgrimage.
And during this period
Muhammad defines the rites of pilgrimage as
they're performed today.
Michael Wolfe has written
extensively about the Hajj
the traditional pilgrimage which every Muslim
is expected to perform at least once.
Two to three million Muslims from
around the world travel to Mecca
every year for this five day ritual,
which takes them in the footsteps of Abraham
the ancient patriarch from whom Muslims,
Jews, and Christians all trace their lineage.
In 1990 Michael Wolfe, a convert to Islam,
took part in his first Hajj.
The Hajj was one of the most
attractive elements
in Islam to me as a non-Muslim and
then as a Muslim.
When I finally became a Muslim
after 20 or more years of thinking it over
the first thing I wanted to do was
make the Hajj.
When I circled the Ka'aba for the first time,
I was in a state of wonder.
You're there with ten of thousands of people,
all doing the same thing at once.
You're literally putting
God at the center of your life.
For that period of time.
At the culmination of the Hajj,
on the Plain of Arafat
on a small hill called the Mount of Mercy,
Muhammad gave his final sermon.
Here is a man who began his mission
as this individual in Mecca, persecuted, with
with almost no followers, and his life
is completed with a valley filled
with tens of thousands of people, uh,
that have accepted his message.
And, and there he is,
preaching to them his final sermon.
And in it in a sense is a summation
of this universal teaching.
He tells them to be good to each other,
and not to violate each other's rights.
For men and women to treat each other
humanely, for brothers and sisters to treat
each other well, and for Muslims to treat
each other as brothers and sisters.
And perhaps most importantly,
he calls an end to revenge, to blood killing
to the vendetta
which has bled this culture terribly
since he was born.
At the end of Muhammad's sermon,
he does not list his achievements.
This man has unified people.
He has taught them monotheism.
He has brought them to peace.
And yet he doesn't mark these
as his accomplishments.
Quite the opposite,
he asks his community
"Have I fulfilled my mission"
"To my God, and to you?"
You can hear in his words the desire
for a completed mission.
This is a man of faith
who is unsure of his affects.
It's a very human moment in which
he needs to know, and he asks
and the people affirm that yes,
three times they say, yes
you have fulfilled your mission.
This, was not a leader who was looking
for his legacy in time.
It wasn't for any purpose other than
to make sure that
when he was going to face his maker,
he was going to be accountable.
And he was, he would be in a position
of saying Allah, I did the best I could.
And, and I hope I was
successful in doing it.
Uh, and that's all what
we can do as human beings.
I think that if I were to say that
I hope to exemplify
any part of Prophet Muhammad's life
it would be the issues around
the dignity near the end of life.
He's a good friend of mine and
I know he knows my voice.
And now I know for sure
he knows my voice.
I'm visiting Mr. Hamoud,
who is a patient that's terminal.
When he was not in the condition
he's in now, he was very delightful
very loving and very much wanting
to tell his story
so we'd sit and listen and talk
for long hours and
he'd give me all his history and his past,
so we're very bonded.
Um, he's slipped into a more terminal stage,
meaning less responsive.
Well he responds,
he's just unable to speak.
Prophet Muhammad has taught us that
near the time of death, the holy Quran
to hear is soothing,
very soothing to the soul.
And since it's a part of our lives
on a daily basis anyway
we derive great comfort from
the hearing of the Quran.
While I'm stroking a head or
I'm speaking softly
I say the things that
I think Muhammad would say.
Prophet
Muhammad has taught us that
we don't even understand,
we could never comprehend
the value of taking care of the ill or
providing for the dying
maintaining their dignity.
And I believe that that's my mission,
to be the helper, to be the listener
to be a comforter in many ways.
The Prophet knew that death was coming
he had an indication that he would not be
around for much longer.
MUHAMMAD had been feeling ill.
He'd had some fever.
It was clear that he was in real difficulty
in terms of his health.
And the household seemed to be convinced that
MUHAMMAD was dying.
And while he was on his deathbed
and there were many who surrounded him,
especially his close companions and his family
he called for silence around him.
And he wanted it to be a time of quiet and
of peace and of calm.
Embraced by the community
he had founded in Medina and
cared for by his wives and companions
Muhammad died peacefully on
June 8th, in the year 632.
The news of his death shocked
his followers, especially Umar
who believed Muhammad
would outlive them all.
People began to hear
the Prophet is dead.
Umar went to the center square and
started to say
there are hypocrites and liars who are
saying that the Prophet is dead.
In the midst of this chaos, Abu Bakr reminded
the Muslims of a verse from the Quran
that had first been revealed
after the battle of Uhud
when they feared that Muhammad
had been killed.
Abu Bakr,
comes into this scene of pandemonium.
And he immediately, uh,
stands up and says
whoever worshipped Muhammad, uh,
then know that Muhammad is dead.
But whoever worshipped God,
know that God lives on and never dies.
And so, suddenly these people are
brought to their senses
that indeed that Muhammad is, is a man.
And men are mortal.
And, and this is his legacy.
He, he did everything within his power
to prevent himself from being worshipped.
Because he recognized that that was a danger
inherent in religious tradition.
That the object of worship
becomes the messenger, and not
uh, the one sending the message.
Prophet Muhammad was a man,
he was flesh and blood
who brought one of the most eloquent
revelations to mankind.
He's set an example
to mankind through his behavior,
through his actions, a living example.
This is a legacy that
he has left for Muslims.
Muhammad's legacy is obviously
the seed that he planted.
It is his righteousness,
his honesty, his integrity
his model as uh as a political leader,
his model as an individual
a man who has uh made great
accomplishments in his time
and yet who didn't let the successes uh
overpower him
didn't let his ego get the best of him.
He remains, I think,
more than anything else a great role model.
MUHAMMAD is the kind of person
who combines political and military and
social and religious
and intellectual dimensions of life
in ways that are important
for those of us in the 21st century
who are struggling to put together
complete lives ourselves.
If I were to have met Prophet Muhammad
on the street, I feel like I would know him.
And as though he would know all of us.
The beauty of it is, we live our lives
through his examples, but he's not God.
Our reverence is to God.
And our reference is to him.
So how I walk, and how I speak,
and how I carry myself
and how I treat my husband, and
how I treat my mother and my father
and how I behave as a sister and a daughter
and a nurse and a friend and a neighbor
that's all prophet Muhammad in action.
There's more about Muhammad and
his legacy on PBS online.
Experience a virtual pilgrimage to Mecca
read essays by people from
the program, and much more.
Visit PBS online at PBS.org
To purchase a videocassette of Muhammad,
or a DVD with additional features,
call 888-786-0444.
Major funding for Muhammad:
Legacy of a Prophet" has been provided by... "
The Corporation for Public Broadcasting
And by...
The David and Lucile Packard Foundation
Arabian Bulk Trade
Sabadia Family Foundation
The El-Hibri Foundation
The Irfan Kathwari Foundation
And Mir Imran
Additional funding has been provided
by many other organizations and individuals.